At the beginning of my education, I felt that I was stimulated in terms of mathematics.
However, I have always liked to keep up with math help and-
-After a while I found an association called Mattehjelpen.
And it is a student association where purpose is-
-To helping students to manage math better.
And it was done mainly by arranging math cabins once a week,
And by holding rehearsal lectures for Mattetentor.
And this was something I involved in,
And I thought it was great fun.
And something that I have always wrestled with-
-In time I have been doing math teaching-
It has to do with our bachelor's project,
As I did on the I-line, or the industrial economy line.
And I did it in system technology and the assignment was to-
-Take a radio controlled car and turn it into a self -driving highway robot.
And then we would equip it with sensors and make it be able to-
-Take exits.
Run on paces.
Able to go an optimized route.
It could keep the distance to a vehicle present.
Such things that one should typically be able to do on a highway.
And here you can see an example of how it went then.
So now the car will take an exit here.
And this is our self -carved course that we have built.
Now it will drive on the highway again.
And then it will take a lap.
And then when it comes to this black line it will now stop.
And this was the first time we succeeded in this,
And it was damn fun.
But, how did this work then?
Well, this robot was equipped with a camera that constantly looked-
It had to do with point detection.
So finding interesting points in pictures.
And what you see here, it's a picture of an EU pallet.
And here you can imagine, for example, an autonomous forklift-
-You want to go away and pick it up.
And then it must know what points it should aim with its forks.
And it had then been-
-The two points.
And the key here, or what one wants to then-
-This is to create a model that automatically based on the contents of the image-
-Can find and dot out what points you want to find.
What I was going to talk in a little more detail about here now,
It is an application from the food industry.
When they are going to package festis cartons for example-
-The they have to put the straw out in the right place on the carton.
And if you don't, so the straw ends up outside,
attention map, which indicates where it is likely-
-That there is a point of interest.
And it is then like a white area.
And in this case, the picture is,
This color image we are looking at,
It is a picture from a mall with lots of people in itself.
These little white areas in the black image-
-There are indications of where these people's heads are.
That was what was of interest.
And a little short just about how this actually went then.
Here you see three relatively simple examples when the straw is placed either-
And-
-You can see this here.
Up to the left you see a straw that is skewed format,
and at the top right you see a straw that has the wrong orientation-
-Against what it really should have.
And we see here that the model is struggling to prick out-
-The right number of points to detect.
And also where these points should detect.
You see it in the form of the red crosses.
Finally then.
What different tracks are there-
Well, you can of course read as a civil or college engineer.
And then it is more theoretical math if you read a civil engineer.
Then of course you can also read to mathematicians.
Then you read a lot of math.
And I can also recommend reading a mix of mathematics and programming.
Because then you will surely be very sought after in the labor market.
And then you can also read to mathematics teachers.
For example for high school,
or for high school.
Then I also just want to mention this track that I am currently on.
This KPU, or supplementary educational education.
If it is so that you have read civil or college engineer-
-or that you have read to mathematicians, so you can complement your education-
-So that you get the right to teach within the school.
And I am currently reading KPU at Liu.
And so far, my experience of education-
-That it is really good and valuable.
Clearly above expectation actually.
Okay, then you've been told a bit of-